COLIN CARGILE

• DETAILS •

New York City, 10025 646-573-5591 cargile10@gmail.com

o SKILLS o

Inventory Management

Time Management Skills

Multitasking Skills

Excellent Customer Service Skills

Merchandising

Solution Selling

Dedicated team player

Digital Photography

Adobe Lightroom

PROFILE

I am an experienced Retail Manager and Photographer with a back-round in sporting goods and hospitality. I strive to build people up to create the best environment for high preforming teams with a commitment to excellent customer service while accentuating organization and attention to detail.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Freelance Photographer at CornerShop App, New York City

October 2020 — Present

Experienced and adventurous photographer committed to capturing life's moments of the world through my lens. Leveraging a background in commercial photography for ecommerce sites like Uber Eats and Amazon Fresh, with a dedication to world-class customer service.

Retail Store Manager at Upper 90 Soccer, New York City

January 2017 — August 2019

- Oversee customer experience efforts of the newest and largest location of a retail sporting goods chain that includes an in-store café, special event facilities, and 3 Adidas-sponsored soccer pitches.
- Direct the store sales team on their customer interactions, sales results, cash handling, register reconciliations, and inventory-taking.
- Strive for repeat business and referrals by supervising team interactions with customers to ensure quality service, product satisfaction, and an excellent customer experience. Coach and train the sales team, as needed.
- Forecast upcoming seasonal demand of each inventory item, monitor stock, and re-order supplies as appropriate to anticipated sales activity.
- Report sales and inventory-on-hand statistics to management and budget departments.
- Schedule work shifts and assignments for employee team.
- Ensure store always is clean and well merchandised.

Assistant Retail Manager at Upper 90 Soccer, New York City

March 2014 — January 2017

- Joined the Upper 90 Soccer company at its flagship Manhattan location.
- Provided expert assistance to customers with recommendations on brand, fit, and style differences, value, durability of products, and their suitability to the skill level of the player
- Worked with the sales team to ensure the store provided high quality, personalized service to meet company standards.
- Processed transactions and handled cash and credit information. Responsible for store opening and/or closing financial accounting.
- · Assisted with ordering inventory.

Line Cook / Assistant Manager at Maoz Vegetarian Restaurant, New York City

May 2010 — February 2014

- Prepared food at a new concept, fast-service vegetarian restaurant.
- Enforced the freshness of the raw food and other ingredients, dated inventory, and rotated stock. Continual quality inspection in the kitchen and other food preparation and serving areas to maintain the cleanliness and safety
- · Supervised the kitchen and support staff.
- Assisted with customer service, payment transactions, and store cleanliness.

Teaching Assistant at Manhattanville College, White Plains

February 2008 — May 2009

- Taught undergraduate-level photography courses as part of teacher certification preparation.
- Selected responsibilities under the direction of the course professor:
 - Led discussion sections, tutorials, or laboratory sections.
 - Demonstrated laboratory equipment and enforced lab rules.
 - Assisted faculty members with lab and field research.
 - Informed students of the procedures for completing and submitting class work, such as lab reports.
 - Served as faculty interface with students, gave and collected assignments, prepared class materials, and assisted with student conferences.

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts, History, Manhattanville College, White Plains

August 2007 — June 2009

Minor in Photography

Bachelor of Arts, History, Brooklyn College, New York City

August 2010 — June 2014

Member of Men's Varsity Soccer Team

Minor in Photography